JEREMY GUAN

Epping, Sydney, NSW 2121

Mobile: 0423700188 Email: jeremy.guan@gmail.com

I am a Sydney-based software and web developer with Seven years industry experience. With a wide range of skills in software and web application development, I have worked in a number of different projects for a variety of clients. My specialties include open source and web technologies, such as Perl/PHP, JavaScript/jQuery, MySQL/PostgreSQL and Linux. Moreover, I am always keeping an open mind and eager to learn new technologies to enhance my career and professional growth.

TECHNICAL OVERVIEW				
Languages	Perl (5+ yrs)	PHP (2 yrs)	JavaScript (5+ yrs)	
Databases	MySQL (5+ yrs)	PostgreSQL (2 yr)	SQL Server (1 yr)	
Web	HTML/CSS (10+ yrs)	HTML5/CSS3 (2 yr)	jQuery (5+ yrs)	ExtJs (1 yr)
	Bootstrap (2 yrs)	Google Charts (1 yr)		
Tools	Apache (5+ yrs)	Subversion (5+ yrs)	Git (1 yr)	Vim (5+ yrs)
CPAN Modules	POE (1 yr)	HTML::Mason (1 yr)	Template Toolkit (5+ yrs)	
	Class::DBI (5+ yrs)	DBIx::Class (1 yr)	Test::WWW::Selenium (2 yrs)	
Frameworks	Catalyst (5+ yrs)	CodeIgniter (2 yrs)		
Numbers in parentheses denote years of experience				

Numbers in parentheses denote years of experience

WORK EXPERIENCE

November 2011 – November 2013

Software and Web Developer at Hutchinson Software Pty Ltd (http://hutchinsonsoftware.com), full-time.

- Designed and developed web applications with CodeIgniter MVC framework and MySQL
- Designed and implemented web user interfaces using various front end technologies including JavaScript/jQuery/HTML/CSS/Bootstrap
- Maintained and supported legacy PHP web application and MySQL
- Modified and enhanced on-going Catalyst web applications and MySQL
- Implemented new requirements and fixed bugs in **Mason** web application driven by **PostgreSQL**
- Built **REST API** in PHP to interact with Windows client application
- Generated complex Excel reports with **PHPExcel** library
- Created automation test scripts in Perl and PHP to perform model tests and front end tests with Selenium
- Added new features to rich Internet application using ExtJs
- Ported legacy CGI::Application web application with Microsoft Access database to CodeIgniter with MySQL
- Migrated company website to **Joomla** CMS with custom template
- Used **Carton** to manage Perl modules dependencies of Catalyst application to simplify installation process
- Installed and configured **Nagios** for automated system monitoring and alerts

October 2006 - October 2011

Software Systems Developer at dbNet Pty Ltd (http://dbnet.com.au), full-time.

- Designed and developed web applications with Catalyst MVC framework and MySQL/PostgreSQL including school zone alert management system, financial management and billing system, data visualisation system for wireless sensor devices, and medical account management system
- Customised and enhanced web user interfaces using JavaScript/jQuery/HTML/CSS/Google
 Charts
- Used POE and other CPAN modules at back end to create Perl scripts and modules to support web
 applicants
- Maintained and supported on-going web applications and databases
- Installed, configured and administered openSUSE Linux, Apache, and MySQL

July 2001 - October 2003

Webmaster at MyDrivers.com (http://www.mydrivers.com), full-time.

• Administered and maintained the high-traffic primary website and mirror sites

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Studies with **Distinction**, University of Wollongong, December 2005 Bachelor of Civil Engineering, ZhengZhou University (China), July 2001

CERTIFICATIONS

- Sun Certified Programmer for the Java 2 Platform, 2006
- Microsoft Certified Database Administrator, 2002
- Microsoft Certified System Engineer, 2002